Thank you
Good Morning!
You may be seated, thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Thank You, Lord.
Viewers, we salute your faith, your time.
Thank you for your patience.
Hallelujah!
Amen.
Glory be to God.
Today we shall talk about building God's character.
There is so much fear.
It is not even situations that kill now;
it is fear of the situation.
Everywhere; even the politics today - fear.
Some decided not to be a politician because of fear.
People just don't know what to do.
The business too - fear.
Everything - fear, fear...
Fear of loss, fear of failure,
fear of sickness and disease,
fear of accusation, fear of today’s politics, even fear of yourself – you are afraid of yourself.
Some people before going to sleep, they call their children saying, "Come, This is where I put the money,
This is where the bank account is,
I have some money with these people,"
but he is afraid he may not wake up.
Because of what we are seeing all over the world;
even among friends - a lot, a lot...
Let's talk about building God's character.
This will take us to some texts in the Bible.
We take first text from the Book of
John 16, from verse 1 to the end.
Actually, the proof text there is verse 33.
When we leave the Book of John 16,
we will have the grace to look at the Book of Isaiah 43.
Take your reading from verse 1 to the end;
that will give you a picture of what we are talking about.
Also, the Book of Psalms will help.
Take your reading from verse 4 to 7.
Also, the Book of Philippians, chapter 4; take your reading from verse 6 to 7.
That will do.
In all - the Book of Joshua, chapter 1, verse 8.
I want to read that Book of John.
When you get home, you have those other Books to read.
Hallelujah.
John 16:
“All this I have told you so that you will not fall away.
They will put you out of the synagogue;
in fact, the time is coming when anyone who kills you will think they are offering a service to God."
That is the right to kill you...
Are you there?
“They will do such things because they have not known the Father or me.
I have told you this, so that when their time comes
you will remember that I warned you about them.
I did not tell you this from the beginning because I was with you.”
Because He was with us, He did not...
Let's go to the verse 33.
“I have told you these things, so that in Me you may have peace.
In this world you will have tribulation.
But take heart! I have overcome the world.”
That will just give us the basis of what we are to talk about.
Hallelujah.
Don't forget that Book of Isaiah;
Isaiah 43 from beginning to the end - that will really help you.
Hallelujah!
Jesus wants to be involved in our lives as mothers.
Take note of that.
That is why He is giving all these warnings and all we are reading about.
He wants to be involved in our lives as mothers.
You know mothers?
Compared to fathers.
Oh my God.
He knows there will be times fear will overwhelm us.
This is why He said, “I pray your faith will not fail”.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you there?
He knows there will be times fear will overwhelm us.
That is why He said to His disciples, "I pray your faith..." -
it means something is coming.
You will begin to say, "Will I be a Christian? Will I pray?"
This is what we are seeing now all over.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Are you seeing them now?
His prophecy is coming to reality.
You are free...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Fear of loss,
fear of failure,
fear of false accusation,
fear of sickness, disease and infirmity,
fear of today’s business and politics -
fear, fear, fear...
Because of that, your focus has changed.
Fear changes focus.
Businessman becomes pastor today, and turns to...
Fear is a more deceptive enemy than satan himself.
More what?
... than satan himself.
Situation doesn’t kill but fear kills.
Sickness doesn’t kill but fear kills.
Before that sickness - a medical report, "Prepare your will" - already you have died...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Fear is a more deceptive enemy than satan.
Many people - they hold on to themselves.
Fear stops us from admitting our guilt.
"No. If I said this, what would happen to me?"
Look at our Lord, Jesus Christ.
The Holy Spirit is the One that sustained Him in the Garden of Gethsemane
when He prayed concerning the cup of suffering.
Holy Spirit sustained Him.
"Oh, let this cup pass over."
The Holy Spirit said to Him, "Don't forget the reason why you are sent.
You are not sent to do Your will, but the will of Father in Heaven.
Oh, let the will of God be done."
It was the Holy Spirit that sustained Him.
Fear, fear, fear - you are even afraid of yourself.
Fear of your children, fear of yourself, fear of your husband, fear of your wife...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You see suicides today.
People commit suicide because of fear.
The rate of suicides is crazy!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is why we have to build God's character.
The funny thing is that
not even our natural gifts, talent, education can help us to overcome fear
but they can only develop and refine us as a natural man to the highest possible point.
That is what education and talent can do;
to the highest possible point,
but cannot sustain you, cannot help you to overcome fear; of sickness, of this of that.
You see many people commit suicide today.
Let someone say, "fear".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Some are here today not because of Jesus,
but because of their boss, mentor, girlfriend, boyfriend;
that is the reason why they are here.
Not that they have faith.
Fear.
Our concern now is to build God’s character.
If you want to become God’s person, a Christian,
born again, you must follow His process.
God’s Word reflects His character.
To build God’s character, to become
God’s person, to become a Christian,
to become born again, you must follow His process.
Let someone say, "His process".
You understand that?
Like women have taken over jeans,
we have taken the soup in the kitchen.
They are the ones putting on jeans now.
Before you know it, the jeans are in the market; trousers -
you see them putting on, they have taken over from us.
In fact, we are ready to wear skirts.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
They should prepare; fashion
designers should get us skirts.
If they have taken over this; the trousers and jeans - everywhere jeans, trousers... women.
We are protesting, so let us also start wearing skirts.
So they will know that we are protesting.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You know, a processing is like making a soup;
they put things together.
If one thing is missing, you miss it all.
That is why when you taste s pepper soup,
you say, "What is this?"
It is because something is missing.
You forgot to add something and you start drinking a pepper soup, but it is sweet.
It is processing.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is God's processing?
Apart from the Bible texts given to you,
when you look at the Book of John 3:5 -
if you are not born of the Spirit, you are not born again.
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a Christian.
If you are not born of the Spirit, you are not a believer.
Because God is Spirit and His worshipers
must worship Him in Spirit and truth.
Simple.
You must follow Him in Spirit.
You must talk to Him in Spirit.
You must relate with Him in Spirit.
If you are not born of Spirit, that is John 3:5, you are not.
And the Book of Romans 8:9-10 says,
“If you don’t have the Spirit of God,
you don’t belong to Him.”
How do we belong to Him?
God’s Word reflects His character.
Since God’s Word reflects His character,
where God speaks, power speaks.
When God walks, power walks.
When God waves, power waves.
When God greets, power greets.
When God talks, power talks.
God's power is working through His Word and His Spirit.
Tell your neighbor, "God's power is
working through His Word and His Spirit".
This is how He walks.
God - power; God talks - power talks.
When you say God, you say power.
Say, "God - power"
That is God for you.
It is like a tap.
You want water somewhere, you just have to turn the tap, and the water will come through the tap.
Through what?
Tap.
He works through His Word and His Spirit to talk to you.
He works through His Word and His Spirit to heal you.
He works through His Word and His Spirit to bless you.
He works through His Word and His Spirit to save you.
We must meditate on what we read in the
Bible and turn it over and over again in our hearts.
The more we mediate, the more
our hearts act upon the Word.
You know; to turn it over and over again in our hearts.
Not just mediation - it is like pounding yam.
You pound it - you want to make it a part of you.
In the process, turn it over and over again in your heart,
in order to do what the Word says.
Not just to hear and preach it, or teach it, but to live by it.
Turn it over.
That is where meditation comes in.
The Bible says, the Word becomes
part of us by meditation.
Let someone say that.
The Word becomes part of us by meditation.
It becomes part of us by meditation.
Turn it over and over again in our hearts.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What is going on in your heart?
Without this meditation, our conduct and character
cannot be influenced by the Word of God.
The more we meditate, the more our
hearts act upon the Word -
the more the Word influences
our conduct and character.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Like you are listening to me, hearing me,
keep your heart in order.
If you don’t get hold of your heart,
your heart will be doing what it likes.
You must have control of your heart.
While you are looking at me, continue that meditation.
For me, I meditate on the Word day
and night and whatever I do prospers.
Viewers, thank you for your time.
Meditate on the Word of God day and night.
No matter how unsteady your life appears
to be, meditate on the Word day and night
and whatever you do will prosper.
Unsteady; your business, your life,
your career, your marriage -
you see, when something is like this you cannot enjoy it.
If I continue walking like this, I cannot enjoy myself.
This is how many, if not all business look like today...
Your marriage...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Viewers, no matter how unsteady
your life, career, business appear to be,
meditate on the Word of God day and night and whatever you do will prosper.
Amen.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Tell your neighbour,
No matter how unsteady your life appears to be, meditate on the Word day and night -
whatever you do prospers.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Instead of wasting your time;
time of prayer, "In the name of Jesus..."
For me, I meditate on the Word day and night.
When I say day and night, I mean,
I turn it over and over again in my heart.
Whatever I do, whatever I say - you will see it any moment from now.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I prayed the way you are praying,
I would not be able to do all this.
The way you pray: you have a book that teaches you how to pray, you list the name of your enemy.
Sometimes you say, "Lord"...
This direction is "Lord", this direction is "Jesus Christ",
this direction is "Jehovah", this direction is "Bread".
After that you do like this...
If I prayed the way you pray,
you would not be here today.
What you have done to me in the past...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You banned me, you rebuked me - well done.
The Spirit of God will be released to the
degree our heart acts upon the Word.
That is why it is very important that
your heart must act upon the Word of God.
Tell your neighbour,
The Spirit of God will be released to the degree, to the measure
your heart acts upon the Word of God.
I mean, the Spirit of God will be
released to the degree, to the measure
we stand in reverence, in honour of His Word.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Where is honour without your heart?
That is the honour we are giving to God today.
You come to church, but your heart is not here.
You worship, many people are dancing
because they see their colleagues dancing.
You know - it is a hobby to dance.
People are dancing, but not with their hearts.
Tell your neighbour,
Where is honour without your heart?
Where is reverence without your heart?
Today, you see people doing... - without their hearts.
That is why there is killing, destruction everywhere.
Your son, daughter, children, wife, husband will wake up, "Good morning, sir" - without their hearts.
That is why after hearing, "Good morning, sir" - at your back anything can happen.
The Spirit of God will be released to the
degree our heart acts upon the Word of God
but your heart does not honour God.
And Christianity lies...
Tell your neighbour,
Without your heart, where is honour?
Without your heart, where is respect?
Without your heart, where is reverence?
This is what is happening all over the world today.
You talk of marriage - marriage without heart.
That is why there is divorce, little things, "No, I saw a letter. No, this is a phone call..." - excuses everywhere.
Divorces because of little.
Marry and re-marry - everywhere.
You see: home, home; divorce, divorce.
It has become a game.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Marriage without heart.
Love without heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Inner my heart
Lord I want to be like Jesus
Marriage without heart is a marriage
that anything can dissolve.
Situation can separate, fight can separate,
whatever can separate,
but a marriage with heart,
"I love you with all my heart" - the love is from heart;
only God can separate such marriage.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
What can separate me from the love of Christ?
Can hatred?
Can fight?
Can killing?
Can death?
What can separate you?
That is a heart for you.
Only God can separate marriage of heart.
In this marriage of heart; "I love you with all my heart. I don't love you because of money, education,
because you are handsome, beautiful. I don't love you because of whatever, just with heart" -
only Jesus...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I want to sing you a song that will make you afraid now.
You will start to say, "What is this?"
On the last day
You see, they refuse to sing along with me.
Only true believers shall be raptured
Do you know
There is another fellowship in Heaven
I know
The Spirit of God which you need to be a Christian, you need to be born again,
you need to be God’s person -
that Spirit will be released to the degree your heart acts.
You can call it ‘immerse’ or ‘immersion’.
... will be released to the degree your heart acts upon the Word of God.
You say, "I need the Spirit of God."
You need it, but it can only be released to the degree, to the measure,
your heart acts; not you.
Heart means your spirit.
... upon the Word of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your consistency in prayer and faithfulness is the only way out.
Your what?
Consistency in prayer and faithfulness is the only way out.
Trust and obey
For there’s no other way
To be happy in Jesus
But to trust and obey
Trust and obey
For there’s no other way
To be happy in Jesus
But to trust and obey
Please, constantly pray in your heart without ceasing.
Without what?
Ceasing.
Do you know what it means?
Constantly pray in your heart.
Are you praying in your heart?
What is the meaning of that?
To pray in the Spirit means to pray in harmony with the Scripture.
Tell your neighbour.
Praising the Lord always
every morning every noon every night
always
Praising the Lord with everything in me
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
Lift your voice and say,
Praising the Lord always
Praising the Lord with all my heart
Open up your mouth and say,
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
Praising the Lord always
As long as I live
In Him I live and move and have my being
Praising the Lord always
Praising the Lord with all my heart
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
Hallelujah
My Lord is good
He is good to me
Hallelujah
My Lord is good
He is good to me
Hallelujah
My Lord is good
He is good to me
Hallelujah
My Lord is good
He is good to me
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated, thank you.
Your enemy loses no time to plot against you;
you should lose no time to commit yourself to the Lord.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You have a section of time to pray, whereas enemy is always busy, at work.
Your enemy is always at work.
That is how they keep getting you.
"Take more of me, give me more of You, oh Lord. Thank You, Lord."
If it is "Thank You, Lord", what you started to say in your heart, it is OK.
"Thank You, Lord... My gracious love. Thank You, Lord..." - that will continue in you heart.
Later it will switch to praising and worship.
Praising the Lord always
Praising the Lord with all my heart
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
Can you see that?
Look at your song - this is the song you are singing, but you are not following it.
Praising the Lord always
Can you listen to that?
‘Always’, that means your heart should continue to praise God.
Prayer; attitude of prayer.
Because a break in prayer will mean a break in faith;
a break in faith is a break with God.
Praising the Lord always
Praising the Lord with all my heart
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
Are you obeying what you are singing?
No!
You are not praising God always.
You allow your heart to be roaming about.
You have to pray – that is the only way you can be filled with the Spirit.
Not this kind of prayer you offer; be on your knee - that is OK,
it is this meditation that will lead you to going on your knee.
I mean; you begin to hear from God Himself.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your enemy loses no time to plot against you and
you should lose no time committing yourself.
This is where we find ourselves today.
We find ourselves in a very messed situation, when it comes to things of the spirit.
Bad situation.
When you are in the business of prayer, constantly praying in your heart without ceasing,
you will only release, “Be healed”.
This is what people will hear, and they will be healed.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That is it!
Sing this song again.
Praising the Lord always
Praising the Lord with all my heart
Praising the Lord with all my heart always
That is all.
This is what I'm expecting in your heart now.
In your heart – constantly praise Him.
Are you singing that song?
While you continue singing this song in your heart, the Spirit of God Himself will switch to prayer,
what to say; He will Himself switch.
You are not in control of your blood.
Are you in control of your blood?
So, you are not to be supposed to be in control of prayer.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are not in control of you blood.
Your blood can cease; you are not in control.
It is just running...
You feel it is running.
In the same day, you are not supposed to be in control of prayer;
the prayer is supposed to switch from praises to prayer,
and when you want to release, you just say, "Be healed, in the name of Jesus. Be delivered in the name...";
people hear this from you.
Look at me; do you see any paper, laptop with me?
I'm talking from the heart.
Message from the heart, not laptop, not paper, not anything.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
I'm not teaching; if I was teaching, I would have carried my laptop, my book.
I'm telling you something from the heart.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
If I was telling you about someone experienced,
I would carried my paper.
No matter how unsteady your career,
business appear to be -
go into the business of praising God in your heart.
The Bible says, we don’t know how to pray; the Spirit helps us in our weaknesses.
In your case it is not Spirit that is helping you.
You have prayer points, and you have the hour to pray,
and if you don't have any situation you don't pray.
What dictates direction of our prayer?
Our situation.
Tell your neighbour.
Our situation dictates the direction of our prayer.
If we are sick, we say, "God, help me, heal me",
but if our everything is alright, we say, "Praise the Lord".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Instead of Holy Spirit, the Spirit of Father to dictate the direction of our prayer, what to pray for...
He helps us in our weaknesses, we don't know how to pray,
but now, our situation dictates the direction of our prayer.
Look at Jesus; Jesus was there with a dead man, His friend.
Instead of Him to say, "Lord, heal, raise!", He said, "Lord, I thank You",
and the Jews and all other were looking at Him, "You should raise the dead and You are saying 'Thank You';
Thank you for killing this man, or for this man to die? What are You saying?"
Tell your neighbour again.
Our situation dictates the direction of our prayer.
When we are sick, we say, "Lord, heal me",
and if we are not healed, we will never say, "Thank You, Jesus".
Until you are healed.
And when you are healed, you say, "Hallelujah!"
Thank you very much.
TT ROBERT BEGIER 31/10/2018
RV LIZZ NDUNGU 14/11/2018